Has uh Hines 57 reached out yet?
>> Uh they haven't reached out to me. Well,
maybe they have. I don't know. I've been
on my phone all day, but I had no idea
that was a thing until after the the
whole pick went down. So, that's pretty
cool.
>> Just about everything I eat. I feel like
fries, burger. I don't know if I could
say hot dog here, but um yeah, just
about everything. So,
>> what is Oh, go ahead.
like coming here, going through
everything and seeing this facility.
>> It it's been awesome. You know, I was I
was fortunate to be able to have a 30
visit here and just talk and meet with
the coaches. Um it just reminded me a
lot of Iowa, just the culture, the
people. Like it truly is a special
place. I can just tell. Um and I'm just
so fortunate and you know, I was hoping
I I'd get the call and, you know, be
able to come play here. So to be able to
do that, it's a dream come true. So,
>> has there been any conversation with any
of the coaches about playing here? What
the plan is in terms of maybe get ready,
take over the spot next year or go earn
the starting spot this year.
>> Yeah, I think the mindset, you know, you
always prepare as if you're a starter,
right? And obviously Garrett Bradberry's
here. He's been in the league for a long
time, you know, and you got a bunch of
other guards, you know, doing Hall of
Famer, right? Like I just get to learn
from them and ask them questions. And
obviously there's a competition part of
it, right? you both compete. Iron
sharpens iron type thing. Um, so, you
know, we'll both get better for it and,
you know, I'm just going to come in and
work as hard as I can.
>> Is there any particular uh center that
you admired uh growing up?
>> Uh, really the one that I watched, um,
you know, being at Iowa's Tyler
Linderbomb, you know, both played at
Iowa, he was he switched over from Dline
to O line just like I did and just
seeing the way he he handled his
business, the way he operated and the
way he played the game. He's somebody I
looked up to for sure. How does playing
center at Iowa with sort of a pro style
offense, how how did that prepare you
for for the NFL?
>> Yeah, you know, Coach Fence and Coach
Barnett, um they're very they prioritize
offensive line play. You know, Coach
Ference, um he's coached offensive line
for a long time and really thinks that's
important. You look at the guys that
have come through there. Um and I was
fortunate to be able to play there,
right? Um, you know, I just think the
way they go about their business, uh,
it's like an NFL, you know, organization
and coach Fence coached in the NFL, too.
So, I think that's where he got it from.
But just very professional in your
approach towards everything you do and
the way you practice. Um, it was never
as much about the on the- field stuff,
but the off the- field stuff, how you
handle your business and your approach.
>> How much time did you spend like
connecting with the quarterbacks that
you work there, whether it's in team
meetings, individually, just getting on
the same page so things work smoothly on
game day? Yeah. Uh, you know, I was
fortunate the quarterbacks I played
with, you know, I was all I was very
close with all of them, you know,
whether it be like a trip down to the
the lake or something like that, but
just communication, right? Like, uh, we
we wanted to take as much off the
quarterback's plate so he can just go
out there and play, you know, he already
has so much on to do and handle. So, if
I can take a little bit off him and, you
know, get the points and things like
that, makes life easier. So, um, as long
as we're on the same page and
communicating, uh, we'll be all right.
>> What do you expect to be the biggest
adjustment? What do you expect to be the
biggest adjustment moving from college
to the NFL?
>> Yeah, I mean the playbook, you know,
after talking with coaches seems like
there's a little bit more on the center
plate here, which is exciting, and just
the terminology, learning all that. Um,
and just being in a new setting, right?
Meeting new guys. Um, and you know,
being a center, you got to be able to go
up there, make a call, and be confident
and have the guys around you trust you.
And that's something you got to earn.
So, it's like being a freshman again.
You got to come in, earn the trust of
everybody, and uh, it'll be fun. I look
forward to it. your thoughts on re
thoughts on reuniting with Tori Taylor.
>> It'll be cool. I haven't talked to Tori
in a while. Uh so it'll be cool to see
him and talk to him. Yeah.
>> You're you're going to be 25, right?
>> Yep.
>> Married.
>> Got married. Yeah.
>> What sort of stepping into a new job
kind of from that premature
point in your life? How do you think
that helps you? You know, one of the
Bear Scouts was saying the other day
because of NIL, you know, the NFL is
going to start getting, you know, older
rookies kind of over the next couple
years. Do you think that you're prepared
now the way you wouldn't have been at
21, 22, stuff like that?
>> Absolutely. And I like going back to
Coach Ference and the way he runs his
program like he just helped me develop
as a man and, you know, understanding
like the importance of, you know,
showing up every day, your like your
approach when you show up to practice,
what your teammates see, and just the
things off the field. Um, you know,
being there for what, six years, it it
definitely helped me grow and who I was
when I got there and who I am now are
just completely different and I think
there's a lot of benefit to that. Um, so
I was just very fortunate. Yeah.
>> So much goes into the job of being a
center in football. What do you do best?
>> You know, I you know, being a center, I
think the most important thing you you
can do is, you know, be a leader and
communicate, right? Um, I think getting
everybody on the same page is is very
important. Um, and then just having
those guys trust you and you know, even
if I make the wrong call, as long as
we're doing it together, uh, that's the
most important thing. So, just
communication for sure.
>> Your ability to to play fast and to play
physical, but also to do it with the
mental part down everything you have to
do in the role of center. What's allowed
you to combine both aspects of your game
that way?
>> Yeah, I think just getting comfortable
with, you know, the playbook and, you
know, having confidence in the guys
around me. Um, understand they know our
offense and what's going on and I can
rely on them and trust them. Um, so even
if you know I go out there, I don't need
to make a call cuz they already know,
you know, where we're working and things
like that. So just having everybody on
the same page mentally, even if you
don't even have to say anything. Um, I
think that's what helped you go out
there and play fast. For sure.
>> It was a runheavy program and, you know,
NFL is a passing league. How do you
think that affects your preparation and
development uh, for this level?
>> Yeah, you know, I think, you know, like
you said, we we ran the ball a lot, but
you know, we passed the ball as well,
especially a little bit more this past
year, too. So, uh, and we transition to
a pro style offense, which is kind of
similar to this offense, which will be
awesome. Obviously, we might pass the
ball a little bit more. Um, so it's it's
a great opportunity for me to work on my
pass protection and things like that,
and it'll be a challenge for sure, but I
look forward to it.
>> There's been some talk about you being a
little undersized for a position, but
obviously that's not a new thing yet.
You've played at a very high level
throughout your career. How have you
managed to do so, although maybe you are
a little undersized? Yeah, you know, the
game's played on the field, you know,
and people try to get all these
measurements and things that don't
matter. Um, but once you step foot on
the field, you know, all that goes away.
Um, it's all about your attitude,
effort, and the way you go about it.
And, you know, being physical,
especially on the offensive line, right?
Like, yeah, I'm going against really
good players, but if my leverage and
everything is, you know, pad and
horizontal, vertical leverage is inside,
I I'll be okay. Um, and as long as my
fundamentals are there, I I'll be all
right. when Iowa asked you to switch
from defensive line to to offense, what
do you remember about that moment? Was
it was it kind of humbling for you?
>> I think it was one of those things I
kind of knew at some point in my career
I' I'd be making the transition and it
was hard, you know, just growing with
the defensive line. Um, but you know,
Coach Fence came to me after Tyler Linum
had left and you know, seeing the
success he had, I was like, you know, I'
I'd be dumb not to listen to you because
obviously you know what you're doing.
Um, and it worked out, right? And it it
wasn't easy at all. You know, the first
couple years very humbling and it still
is very humbling. Uh it's a tough
position, but just continuing to grow
and trust in the process, our coaches
and everything kind of worked out.
>> Did you know so much was expected of the
center position at that like when you
switch?
>> Did you know how much work centers
actually put put into things? Like what
was what kind of a shock was that?
>> Yeah, I think you know being young, you
know, my my first thought is I'm going
to be like Tyler, right? um it should be
easy. Uh no, it it was the exact
opposite. Um you know, I was young, you
know, I wanted to play at a super high
level, but I think the biggest thing was
just my mental capacity for handling
things and being confident and making
sure everybody's on the same page. I
wasn't just there yet, you know, being a
vocal leader. So, that's something I had
to grow into for sure. And that's
that's, you know, the area of my game
that I think early on in my career I
needed the most improvement. Um and I'm
still continuing to improve in that. So
yeah, that for